A Guide to the Papers of Ambrose Bierce, 1842-1914
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Ambrose Bierce, 1842-1914
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
5992 through 5992-r
This collection consists of more than 500 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gifts and deposits of Clifton Waller Barrett; purchases from the Barrett fund.
Contents List
- Military Papers & Correspondence
  - Letter from C.E. Hayes (Top.Engr., 2nd Div.) to Lt. A.G. Bierce 1863 JUL 14, ALS. 1 p. (Box 1)
    [#5992-a]
  - Letter from Capt. John W. Steele (Top.Engr., 2nd Div.) to Lt. A.G. Bierce 1863 OCT 7, ALS. 1 p. (Box 1)
  - Letter from Brig.Gen. W[illiam]; B[abcock] Hazen (2nd Brig., 3rd Div.) to Genl. Lyne Starling(?) (Asst.Adj.Gen.) 1863 OCT 15, ALS. 1 p. (Box 1)
    - Attachment: docket/summary, endorsed 1863 OCT/NOV (Box 1)
      re: military personnel recommendations
  - Letter from Capt. William C. Morgedant(?) (Supt., Topographical Office), to Lt. A.G. Bierce 1863 OCT 18, ALS. 1 p. (Box 1)
  - Military map of Brown's Ferry, TN "drawn by Lt. A.G. Bierce at the command of Gen. Hazen" 1863 NOV, ADS. 1 p. (Box 1)
  - Letter from Brig.Gen. W[illiam]; B[abcock] Hazen (2nd Div. 15th Army Corps) to the Asst.Adj.Gen. (H.Q. - Atlanta, GA) 1864 SEP 30, ALS. 1 p. (Box 1)
    - Attachment: docket/summary, endorsed 1863 OCT/NOV (Box 1)
      Re: military personnel recommendation
  - Special Order 119 assigning 1st.Lt. Ambrose G. Bierce to duty in 3rd Div. 4th Army Corps, signed Brig.Gen. S. Beatty 1864 DEC 6, ADS. 1 p. (Box 1)
  - Directive stating that material "stored in warehouse in Selma (AL)" will be delivered to A[mbrose] G. Bierce. signed by Asst.Spec.Adj. S.B. Eaton 1865 JAN 5, ADS. 1 p. (Box 1)
  - Letter from S.B. Eaton to A[mbrose] J. Bierce 1865 [MAR?] 12, Tgram. 1 p. (Box 1)
  - Bound leather topographical notebook, containing surveys, geological and travel notes by Bierce. 1865 JAN-DEC, AMS (Box 1)
    [#5992]
  - Letter from Capt. H.S. Brown to A.S. Bierce 1866 JUL 31, Tgram. 1 p. (Box 1)
  - Letter from Asst.Adj.Gen. J.C. Kelton to Brev.Maj. Ambrose G. Bierce 1866 OCT 22, LS. 1 p. (Box 1)
  - Enclosure: Presidential commission 1866 AUG 3 (Box 1)
    appointing Ambrose G. Bierce a Brevet Major, effective 1865 MAR 13.
  - Letter from Asst.Adj.Gen. J.C. Kelton to Lafayette Burr 1867 JAN 11, ALS. 1 p. (Box 1)
  - Letter from Asst.Adj.Gen. J.C. Kelton to Ambrose G. Bierce 1867 APR 3, Tgram (Box 1)
  - Letter from W[illiam] B. Hazen to [Ambrose] Bierce 1879 MAY 22, ALS. 3 p. (Box 1)
  - Letter from Alex L. Whitehall to "Comrade Bierce," 1884 NOV 28, ALS. 2 p. (Box 1)
  - Letter from Asst.Adj.Gen. A.D. Greene to Ambrose G. Bierce 1885 FEB 16, LS. 1 p. (Box 1)
  - Letter from W[illiam]; B[abcock] Hazen (Chief Signal Officer) to [Ambrose] Bierce 1885 [DEC 3], ALS. 1 p. (Box 1)
  - Letter from Asst.Adj.Gen. Thomas Ward to Ambrose Bierce 1885 DEC 29, LS. 1 p. (Box 1)
  - Statement of military service of Ambrose G. Bierce in Indiana Volunteers by Adj.Gen. George M. Koontz 1886 JAN 14, L copy. 2 p. (Box 1)
  - Letter from E. Willard to Ambrose Bierce 1886 MAR 25, TLS. 1 p. (Box 1)
  - Letter from Harry J. Kellogg to Maj. A[mbrose] G. Bierce 1886 APR 26, ALS. 1 p. (Box 1)
  - Letter from [Congressman] Wm. W. Morrow to A.G. Bierce 1886 JUL 10, TLS. 1 p. (Box 1)
  - "Special Orders, No. 183" amending Bierce's service record, by order of Lt.Gen. Sheridan issued by Adj.Gen. R.C. Drum, signed by Asst.Adj.Gen. J.C. Kelton 1886 AUG 9, DS. 1 p. (Box 1)
    - Endorsement: Payroll adjustment 1887 APR 21 (Box 1)
      Signed by Acting 2nd Comptroller [P.?] McMahon
  - Letter from Acting Adj.Gen. J.C. Kelton to Congressman W[illiam] W. Morrow 1886 AUG 18, ALS. 1 p. (Box 1)
  - Letter from Brig./Brev/Maj.Gen. W[illiam]; B[abcock] Hazen (Chief Signal Officer) to Commissioner of Pensions 1886 DEC 20, L copy. 2 p. (Box 1)
    - Attachment: notarization 1887 JAN 11 (Box 1)
  - Letter from U.S. Treasury Dept. Auditor [William A. Day] to Ambrose G. Bierce, c/o W[illia]m W. Morrow 1887 JAN 26, LS. 1 p. (Box 1)
  - Letter from Isaac C.B. Suman to Capt. A[mbrose] G. Bierce 1894 MAR 25, ALS. 1 p. (Box 1)
  - Letter from John Eastman to Ambrose Bierce 1897 JUN 17, ALS. 3 p. (Box 1)
  - Letter from John Eastman to [Ambrose] Bierce 1897 JUL 13, ALS. 5 p. (Box 1)
  - Letter from Corr.Sec. Alex L. Whitehall (9th Regt. Indiana Vols.) to Lt. Ambrose Bierce 1903 NOV 8, ALS. 2 p. (Box 1)
  - Letter from Alex L. Whitehall to "Comrade Bierce" 1904 SEP 25, ALS. 3 p. (Box 1)
  - Letter from Sgt. N.V. Brower (Co. I, 9th [Indiana Vols]) to Capt. Ambrose Bierce 1905 MAR 1, ALS. 3 p. (Box 1)
  - Letter from U.S. Dept. of the Interior Commissioner V. Warner to A.G. Bierce 1907 JUN 29, APCS (Box 1)
  - Letter from Brig.Gen. W.W. Wotherspoon (President, Army War College) to Maj. Ambrose Bierce 1908 SEP 29, TLS. 2 p. (Box 1)
  - Letter from Brig.Gen. W.W. Wotherspoon (President, Army War College) to Maj. Ambrose Bierce 1908 OCT 1, TLS. 1 p. (Box 1)
  - Letter from Brig.Gen. W.W. Wotherspoon (President, Army War College) to Maj. Ambrose Bierce 1908 OCT 16, TLS. 2 p. (Box 1)
  - Letter from Lyon & Lyon (attorneys-at-law) to Ambrose G. Bierce 1909 FEB 24, TLS. 1 p. (Box 1)
  - U.S. Dept. of the Interior transmittal of Ambrose Bierce's "reissue" pension [not present], evidently executed by Lyon & Lyon (attorneys-at-law) and submitted for fee to the U.S. Pension Agency 1909 APR 8, DS. 1 p. (Box 1)
    - Endorsement: stamped signature of Commissioner of Pensions J.L. Davenport and agency docket 1909 APR 10 (Box 1)
  - Certificate of service of Ambrose G. Bierce, signed by Adj.Gen. Geo[rge] W. McCay (Executive Dept., State of Indiana) 1910 MAR 19, DS. 1 p. (Box 1)
  - Letter from Albert [Bierce] to "My dear Brother," recounting "my story of [the Battle of] Chickamauga" 1911 MAR 29, ALS. 13 p. (Box 1)
  - Letter from Archibald Gracie to Maj. Ambrose Bierce 1911 MAY 26, TLS. 1 p. (Box 1)
  - Letter from Archibald Gracie to Maj. Ambrose Bierce 1911 JUL 1, TLS. 1 p. (Box 1)
  - Letter from Arch[ibal]d Gracie to Maj. [Ambrose] Bierce 1911 JUL 22, ALS. 2 p. (Box 1)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Col. [Archibald] Gracie 1911 JUL 24, L copy. 3 p. (Box 1)
  - Letter from Archibald Gracie to Maj. Ambrose Bierce 1911 AUG 17, TLS. 2 p. (Box 1)
  - Letter from Arch[ibald] Gracie to Maj. [Ambrose] Bierce 1911 AUG 30, ALS. 2 p. (Box 1)
  - Letter from Archibald Gracie to Maj. [Ambrose] Bierce 1911 SEP 23, ALS. 4 p. (Box 1)
  - Letter from S[olomon]; S[olis] Carvalho to Ambrose Bierce 1911 DEC 6, TLS. 1 p. (Box 1)
    - Attachment: Newsclipping n.d. (Box 1)
      Re: death of John C. Eastman's mother, Harriet A. Eastman
  - Letter from Commissioner of Pensions J.L. Davenport to Ambrose G. Bierce 1912 MAY 16, APCS (Box 1)
  - Letter from Commissioner of Pensions receipt for declaration awarded to Ambrose G. Bierce 1912 NOV 16, D. 1p. (Box 1)
  - Notarized statement re: Bierce's date of birth (a copy with original signatures of Ambrose Bierce and Notary Public W. Hayden Collins) 1913 APR 30, DS. 1 p. w/ docket (Box 1)
  - Pension certificate awarded to Ambrose G. Bierce, signed by U.S. Secretary of the Interior M? K. Lane 1913 JUL 9, DS. 1p. w/ docket (Box 1)
  - Letter from Alex L. Whitehall (secretary, 9th Regt. Indiana Vols.) to Mrs. H[elen Bierce] D. Cowden 1915 JAN 9, ALS. 4 p. (Box 1)
- General Correspondence
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Mr. [Crawford] Wilson [1872 ?], ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Mr. [Crawford] Wilson 1875 APR 22, ALS. 3 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from A[mbrose] G. Bierce to Mssrs. McLaughlin & Steele 1883 DEC 6, L copy. 4 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from A[mbrose] G. Bierce to [Edward L.G.] Steele [1883 DEC 21], ALS. 8 p. (Box 2)
    [#5992-f]
  - Letter from A[mbrose] G. Bierce to [Edward L.G.] Steele [1884] JAN 4, ALS. 4 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from A[mbrose] G. Bierce to [Edward L.G.] Steele 188[4] JAN 11, ALS. 3 p. (Box 2)
    (letter is misdated 1883 by Bierce) [#5992-f]
  - Letter from Leigh Bierce to [Edward L/G.] Steele 1884 JAN 11, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from A[mbrose] G. Bierce to Mssrs. McLaughlin & Steele 1884 JAN 16, L copy. 4 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from A[mbrose] G. Bierce to [Edward L.G.] Steele [1884 FEB 6], ALS. 4 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from A[mbrose] G. Bierce to [Edward L.G.] Steele [1884 FEB 18], ALS. 3 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from A[mbrose] G. Bierce to [Edward L.G.] Steele [1884] FEB 25, ALS. 4 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from A[mbrose] G. Bierce to [Edward L.G.] Steele 1884 MAR 13, ALS. 3 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from A[mbrose] G. Bierce to [Edward L.G.] Steele 1884 APR 5, ALS. 4 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from A[mbrose] G. Bierce to [Edward L.G.] Steele [1884 APR 11], ALS. 3 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from A[mbrose] G. Bierce to [Edward L.G.] Steele [1884 APR 15], ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from [Ambrose G.] B[ierce] to [Edward L.G.] Steele [1884 APR 22], ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from A[mbrose] G. Bierce to [Edward L.G.] Steele [1884 MAY 5], ALS. 4 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from A[mbrose] G. Bierce to [Edward L.G.] Steele 1884 MAY 8, ALS. 3 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from A[mbrose] G. Bierce to [Edward L.G.] Steele 1884 MAY 15, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from A[mbrose] G. Bierce to [Edward L.G.] Steele 1884 MAY 25, ALS. 3 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from A[mbrose] G. Bierce to [Edward L.G.] Steele 1884 AUG 1, ALS. 3 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from A[mbrose] G. Bierce to [Edward L.G.] Steele [1884 AUG 2], ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from A[mbrose] G. Bierce to [Edward L.G.] Steele 1884 AUG 4, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from A[mbrose] G. Bierce to [Edward L.G.] Steele 1884 AUG 10, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from A[mbrose] G. Bierce to [Edward L.G.] Steele 1884 AUG 15, ALS. 9 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from A[mbrose] G. Bierce to [Edward L.G.] Steele 1884 AUG 21, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from [Ambrose G.] B[ierce] to [Edward L.G.] Steele [1884 SEP], ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from A[mbrose] G. Bierce to [Edward L.G.] Steele [1884] DEC 24, ALS. 3 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from A[mbrose] G. Bierce to [Edward L.G.] Steele 1885 JAN 5, ALS. 4 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from A[mbrose] G. Bierce to [Edward L.G.] Steele [1885 JAN/FEB], ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from A[mbrose] G. Bierce to Mssrs. McLaughlin & Steele 1885 FEB 26, L copy. 4 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from A[mbrose] G. Bierce to [Edward L.G.] Steele 1885 MAR, ALS. 4 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from T.H. Readen (NY Superior Court judge) to Mrs. Mollie? Bierce 1885 DEC 12, ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 2)
  - Letter from A[mbrose] G. B[ierce] to [Edward L.G.] Steele [1885 DEC], ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from E[dward] L.G. Steele to "Eddie" [his son] 1886 JUN 26, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
    [#5992-b]
  - Letter from E[dward] L.G. Steele to his wife 1886 JUN 27, ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 2)
  - Letter from E[dward] L.G. Steele to his wife 1887 JUL 8, ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 2)
  - Letter from E[dward] L.G. Steele to his wife 1887 JUL 30, ALS. 1 p. w/ env. (Box 2)
  - Letter from A[mbrose] G. Bierce to [Edward L.G.] Steele [1887 JUL], ALS. 3 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from A[mbrose] G. Bierce to [Edward L.G.] Steele 1887 DEC 12, ALS. 3 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from Arthur McEwen to Ambrose Bierce [c. 1888 JUL], ALS. 3 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from A[mbrose] G. Bierce to [Edward L.G.] Steele 1889 JAN 13, ALS. 3 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from A[mbrose] G. B[ierce] to [Edward L.G.] Steele [1889] JAN, ALS. 4 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from E[dward] L.G. Steele to his wife 1889 MAR 5, ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 2)
  - Letter from E[dward] L.G. Steele to his wife 1889 MAR 11, ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 2)
    - Enclosures: invoice of Hotel del Coronado and invitation card of Mrs. Homer S. King 1889 MAR 14 (Box 2)
  - Letter from E[dward] L.G. Steele to his wife 1889 JUN 18, ALS. 1 p. w/ env. (Box 2)
  - Letter from E[dward] L.G. Steele to his wife 1889 JUN 19, ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 2)
  - Letter from E[dward] L.G. Steele to his wife 1889 JUN 20, ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 2)
  - Letter from E[dward] L.G. Steele to his wife 1889 JUN 24, ALS. 1 p. w/ env. (Box 2)
  - Letter from E[dward] L.G. Steele to his wife 1889 JUL 29, ALS. 1 p. w/ env. (Box 2)
  - Letter from E[dward] L.G. Steele to his wife 1890 JUN 9, ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 2)
  - Letter from E[dward] L.G. Steele to his wife 1890 JUN 10, ALS. 1 p. w/ env. (Box 2)
  - Letter from E[dward] L.G. Steele to his wife 1890 JUN 16, ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to Ambrose Bierce 1891 FEB 24, ALS. 3 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from Arthur McEwen to "My dear Shortridge" 1891 MAR 22, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from Agreement for Ambrose Bierce to publish "The Monk and the Hangman's Daughter," an adaptation of of a story by G.A. Danziger 1891 JUN 18, TM. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from E[dward] L.G. Steele to his wife 1891 JUN 19, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 2)
  - Letter from E[dward] L.G. Steele to his wife 1891 JUN 25, ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 2)
  - Letter from E[dward] L.G. Steele to his wife 1891 JUL 25, ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to Ambrose Bierce 1891 SEP 24, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from Promissory note, Ambrose Bierce to G.A. Danziger 1891 SEP 25, ANS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    - Endorsed: by G.A. Danziger 1892 MAY 2 (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to Ambrose Bierce 1891 SEP 28, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to Ambrose Bierce 1891 OCT 2, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to Ambrose Bierce 1891 OCT 6, ALS. 6 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to [Ambrose Bierce] 1891 OCT 15, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. D[anziger] to Ambrose Bierce 1891 OCT 28, ALS. 3 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to Ambrose Bierce 1891 NOV 3, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to [Ambrose Bierce] 1891 NOV 9, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from [G.A.] D[anziger] to [Ambrose Bierce] 1891 NOV 17, ALS. 4 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from [G.A.] D[anziger] to [Ambrose Bierce] 1891 NOV 20, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from [G.A.] Danziger to [Ambrose Bierce] 1891 DEC 2, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from [G.A.] Danziger to [Ambrose Bierce] 1891 DEC 3, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to Ambrose Bierce 1891 DEC 15, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from [G.A.] Danziger to Ambrose Bierce 1891 DEC 23, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from [G.A.] Danziger to Ambrose Bierce 1891 DEC 31, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from [G.A.] D[anziger] to Ambrose Bierce 1892 JAN 6, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from [G.A.] Danziger to Ambrose Bierce 1892 JAN 8, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from [G.A.] Danziger to Ambrose Bierce 1892 JAN 14, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from [G.A.] Danziger to Ambrose Bierce 1892 JAN 19, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to Ambrose Bierce 1892 JAN 30, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from Joseph R. Folsom to [George Haven] Putnam 1892 FEB 1, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
    Refers to earlier correspondence between Putnam and Ambrose Bierce concerning the publication of his book, Tales of Soldiers and Civilians, which was eventually published in San Francisco by Bierce's friend, E.L.G. Steele in 1891. Bierce had claimed that he could not get an Eastern publisher to accept his book for publication, but this letter indicates Putnam had made Bierce an offer which he refused. [#5992-i]
  - Letter from [G.A.] Danziger to Ambrose Bierce 1892 FEB 3, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from [G.A.] Danziger to Ambrose Bierce 1892 FEB 3, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from [G.A.] D[anziger] to Ambrose Bierce 1892 FEB 15, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from [G.A.] Danziger to Ambrose Bierce 1892 FEB 24, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to Ambrose Bierce 1892 FEB 27, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from [G.A.] Danziger to Ambrose Bierce 1892 MAR 4, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from [G.A.] Danziger to Ambrose Bierce 1892 MAR 14, ALS. 3 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from [G.A.] Danziger to Ambrose Bierce 1892 MAR 22, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to Ambrose Bierce 1892 MAR, Tgram. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from [G.A.] Danziger to Ambrose Bierce 1892 APR 5, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from [G.A.] Danziger to Ambrose Bierce 1892 APR 6, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from [G.A.] D[anziger] to Ambrose Bierce 1892 APR 8, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to Ambrose Bierce 1892 APR 15, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to Ambrose Bierce 1892 APR 23, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to Ambrose Bierce 1892 APR 28, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to Ambrose Bierce 1892 MAY 2, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from [G.A.] D[anziger] to Ambrose Bierce 1892 MAY 7, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. D[anziger] to Ambrose Bierce 1892 MAY 24, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from [G.A.] Danziger to Ambrose Bierce 1892 JUN 9, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to Ambrose Bierce 1892 JUN 14, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to Ambrose Bierce 1892 JUN 18, ALS. 4 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. D[anziger] to Ambrose Bierce 1892 JUN 20, ALS. 6 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to Ambrose Bierce 1892 JUN 23, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from [G.A.] Danziger to Ambrose Bierce 1892 JUN 27, ALS. 4 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to Ambrose Bierce 1892 JUL 8, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to Ambrose Bierce 1892 JUL 14, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. D[anziger] to Ambrose Bierce 1892 JUL 16, ALS. 3 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from Adolf Danziger to Ambrose Bierce 1892 JUL 18, ALS. 4 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. D[anziger] to Ambrose Bierce 1892 JUL 20, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. D[anziger] to Ambrose Bierce 1892 JUL 23, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from Gus A. Danziger to Ambrose Bierce 1892 JUL 29, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. D[anziger] to [Ambrose] Bierce 1892 AUG 5, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1892 AUG 9, ALS. 5 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from [G.A. Danziger] to [Ambrose] Bierce 1892 AUG 10, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1892 AUG 13, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1892 AUG 16, ALS. 8 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from A[mbrose]; B[ierce] to [Edward L.G.] Steele 1892 AUG 21, ALS. 3 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. D[anziger] to [Ambrose] Bierce 1892 AUG 22, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    [ #5992-a]
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1892 AUG 23, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1892 AUG 26, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from [G.A.] D[anziger] to [Ambrose] Bierce 1892 AUG 27, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. D[anziger] to [Ambrose] Bierce 1892 AUG 29, ALS. 4 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1892 AUG 31, ALS. 7 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1892 SEP 1, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. D[anziger] to [Ambrose] Bierce 1892 SEP 2, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. D[anziger] to [Ambrose] Bierce 1892 SEP 3, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1892 SEP "Labor Day", ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1892 SEP 6, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1892 SEP 12, ALS. 4 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1892 SEP 14, ALS. 3 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1892 SEP 14, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. D[anziger] to [Ambrose] Bierce 1892 SEP 15, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. D[anziger] to [Ambrose] Bierce 1892 SEP 16, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. D[anziger] to [Ambrose] Bierce 1892 SEP 19, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. D[anziger] to [Ambrose] Bierce 1892 SEP 21, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1892 SEP 25, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
    - Enclosure: Printed advertisement for "Black Beetles in Amber" (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1892 SEP 27, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1892 SEP 28, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1892 SEP 30, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1892 OCT 3, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [G.A.] Danziger 1892 OCT 5, L copy. 4 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1892 OCT 5, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [G.A.] Danziger 1892 OCT 10, L copy. 3 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1892 OCT 11, ALS. 4 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [G.A.] Danziger 1892 OCT 12, L copy. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [G.A.] Danziger 1892 OCT 12, L copy. 3 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1892 OCT 13, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [G.A.] Danziger 1892 OCT 14, L copy. 3 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [G.A.] Danziger 1892 OCT 17, L copy. 3 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1892 OCT 18, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1892 NOV 9, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1892 NOV 12, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1892 NOV 14, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1892 NOV 16, ALS. 3 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1892 NOV 17, ALS. 4 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from [G.A]. D[anziger] to [Ambrose] Bierce 1892 NOV 22, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from [G.A]. Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1892 NOV 22, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Blanche [Partington] 1892 NOV 29, ALS. 3 p. w/ transcript (Box 2)
    - Pasted in Letters of Ambrose Bierce with ANSno date, Blanche Partington and an inscribed photograph
      [Barrett PS 1097 .Z5A3 1922a c.2]
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1892 DEC 12, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1892 DEC 18, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [G.A.] Danziger 1892 DEC 19, L copy. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1892 DEC 21, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1892 DEC 31, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1893 JAN 17, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from [G.A.] Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1893 JAN 25, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1893 JAN 31, ALS. 6 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [G.A.] Danziger 1893 FEB 1, ALS. 5 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1893 FEB 4, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [G.A.] Danziger 1893 FEB 7, ALS. 6 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1893 FEB 9, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [G.A.] Danziger 1893 FEB 11, L copy. 5 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1893 FEB 13, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from E[dward] L.G. Steele to his wife 1893 MAR 11, ALS. 4 p. w/ env. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1893 MAR 13, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1893 MAR 31, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from E[dward] L.G. Steele to his wife 1893 APR 17, ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 2)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1893 APR 19, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from E[dward] L.G. Steele to his wife 1893 APR 21, ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 2)
  - Letter from "Mama" [Mrs. Ambrose Bierce] to her daughter, Ray? ("Bib") Bierce 1893 APR 23, AL. 5 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to E[dward] L.G. Steele 1893 APR 27, Tgram. 1 p. (Box 2)
    [#5992--b]
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1893 MAY 1, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    - Enclosure: Invoice 1893 APR 25